Guide to the Washington Association of Wheat Growers Records 1955-1977
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Washington Association of Wheat Growers Records
1955-1977
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 370
Washington Association of Wheat Growers
6 containers. 5.6 linear feet of shelf space. 3100 items.
Correspondence, minutes, directories, financial and other records of the wheat growers of Washington. Included are materials from the National Association of Wheat Growers.
The Washington Association of Wheat Growers was incorporated in January 1955. The expressed purposes of the organization are to: (1) improve strains and by-products, (2) develop new markets, (3) conserve natural resources, and (4) promote the interests of wheat growers. Headquartered in Ritzville, the Washington Association of Wheat Growers is a corporate member of the National Association of Wheat Growers.
Correspondence, minutes, directories, financial and other records of the wheat growers of Washington. Included are materials from the National Association of Wheat Growers.
The records of the Washington Association of Wheat Growers are arranged in two series. The first series consists of the organization's administrative files for the years 1955 through 1977. The folders within each subseries are arranged alphabetically. The subseries include conventions, correspondence, personnel directories, environment, organizational finances, legislation, membership meeting minutes, product improvement, and product promotion. The second series, National Association of Wheat Growers, contains correspondence, financial records, meeting data, and reports of the national group from 1956 through 1977. Within each series, the folders are arranged alphabetically.
This collection is open for research use.
The records of the Washington Association of Wheat Growers were donated to the Washington State University Libraries by the Association through Executive Secretary Don Munkers in October 1977 (77-63).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Muckers, Don. WaPS
Washington Association of Wheat Growers--Archives; National Association of Wheat Growers (U.S.)
Agriculture -- Washington (State) -- Societies, etc. -- Records and correspondence; Wheat -- Washington (State)
Agriculture; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: Administrative Records
  - Convention, 1955 - 1976
    - Convention Addresses (cassettes), undated; 9 (Box 1, Folder 2-Jan)
    - Convention Materials, 1955-1975.; 370 (Box 1, Folder 9-Mar)
    - Convention Proceedings, 1955-1976.; 25 (Box 1, Folder 13-Oct)
    - Panel Discussions (cassettes), undated; 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Past Conventions Income and Expenses, 1971-1972.; 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1955 - 1975
    - Agreement Contracts, 1969-1972.; 12 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, 1971-1973.; 2 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Assessment Increase, 1973; 70 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
    - Association of Associations, 1973; 10 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Board of Directors, 1974; 11 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Columbia Plateau Resources, 1966-1972.; 5 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1973.; 20 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Crank Letters, 1973-1974.; 5 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Equipment, 1967-1973.; 55 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Executive Committee, 1975; 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Executive Correspondence, 1972-1975.; 5 (Box 2, Folder 27-31)
    - Executive Secretary, 1968-1973.; 15 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Feed Utilization, 1974; 1 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Great Plains Wheat, 1973; 5 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Inland Waterways, 1960-1968.; 15 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Insurance, 1969-1972.; 10 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - International Wheat Agreements, 1964-1971; 15 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - International Wheat Council, 1969-1973.; 5 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Labor Relations, 1973-1974.; 45 (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
    - Lawyer Retainer Agreement, 1958-1967.; 8 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Leadership Workshop, 1973; 3 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Limitations Payments, 1969; 1 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Oregon Wheat Commission, 1967; 1 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Pacific Northwest Crop Improvement Association, 1964; 3 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Paper Inventory, 1972; 7 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Postal Inquiry, 1975; 5 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - President, 1973-1975.; 30 (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
    - Resolutions, 1959-1960.; 45 (Box 2, Folder 50-51)
    - Soil Conservation Service, 1965; 4 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - South American Market Development, 1973; 1 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Supply Prices and Contracts, 1969-1971.; 1 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Symbol and Jewelry, 1966-1972.; 12 (Box 2, Folder 55-56)
    - Washington Crop Improvement Association, 1969-1973.; 5 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Washington State Farm Bureau, 1973; 1 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Washington Wheat Commission, 1969-1975.; 40 (Box 2, Folder 59-60)
    - Western Wheat Commission, 1973-1974.; 5 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Wheat Marketing Order, 1955-1958.; 25 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Xerox, 1971; 10 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Directories
    - County officers, 1956-1959.; 20 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Lists, 1970-1976.; 21 (Box 2, Folder 65-66)
    - Personnel Bulletins, 1961-1977.; 12 (Box 2, Folder 67-68)
  - Environment
    - Drift Study, 1973-1974.; 40 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Ecology, 1962-1974.; 130 (Box 2, Folder 70-74)
    - Pesticide Regulation, 1972-1974.; 38 (Box 2, Folder 75-76)
  - Finances, 1955-1974
    - Account Budgets, 1968-1970.; 45 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Accounts Receivable Ledger, 1966-1969.; 1 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Budget, 1971-1974.; 65 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - County Dues Payment, 1973; 6 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - County Financial Records, 1957-1958.; 15 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - County Financial Reports, 1955-1956.; 20 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Financial Reports, 1956-1964; 50 (Box 3, Folder 83-85)
    - Financial Statements, 1957-1974.; 47 (Box 3, Folder 86-89)
    - Journal, 1955; 1 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Ledgers, 1957-1966. (oversize); 3 (Box 3, Folder 91-93)
    - Taxes, 1958-1972.; 102 (Box 3, Folder 94-101)
    - Telephone Credit Cards, 1972-1973.; 13 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Legislative, 1955-1975
    - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, 1966; 4 (Box 3, Folder 103-105)
    - Enabling Act, 1955-1956.; 81 (Box 3, Folder 106-107)
    - Formation of the Wheat Commission, 1957; 1 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - House Bill 389, 1961; 1 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - House Resolution, undated; 1 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Lobbyist, 1971-1975.; 30 (Box 4, Folder 111-112)
    - National Legislation, 1972-1974.; 85 (Box 4, Folder 113-114)
    - State Legislation, 1971-1974.; 50 (Box 4, Folder 115-116)
    - Superior Court Summons, 1961; 1 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Wheat Allotment Records, 1956-1967.; 15 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Membership, 1967-1974.
    - Records, 1967-1974.; 75 (Box 4, Folder 119-122)
  - Minutes, 1954-1974
    - Board Minutes, 1954-1974.; 215 (Box 4, Folder 123-131)
    - Minutes, Board of Directors, 1955-1966; 12 (Box 5, Folder 132-144)
  - Product Improvement, 1964-1975.
    - Development Research, 1973-1975.; 5 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Dockage Revision, 1975; 4 (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Feed Usage, 1964-1974.; 30 (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Marketing, 1974; 45 (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Production Research, 1972-1974.; 25 (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Transportation, 1971-1975.; 60 (Box 5, Folder 150-152)
    - Transportation, Alaska Ammonia, 1973-1974.; 30 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Product Promotion, 1957-1977
    - Domestic Utilization, 1962-1974.; 27 (Box 5, Folder 154-155)
    - Educational Information, 1968-1974.; 27 (Box 5, Folder 156-159)
    - Museum, 1967; 16 (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - News Releases, 1970-1975.; 50 (Box 5, Folder 161-162)
    - Postal Permits, 1957-1973.; 165 (Box 5, Folder 163-164)
    - Price Determinants, 1974; 1 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Publications, 1977; 8 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Trade Teams, 1968-1969.; 35 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Wheat Life, 1974-1977.; 30 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Wheat Life Requests, 1970-1973.; 13 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Wheat-O-Gram, 1973-1976.; 175 (Box 5, Folder 170-171)
    - Wheat Queen, 1969-1974.; 30 (Box 5, Folder 172-173)
    - Wheat Queen Scrapbook, 1966-1968.; 1 (Box 5, Folder 174 (oversize))
- Series 2: National Association of Wheat Growers, 1956-1977
  - Committee Reports, 1972-1973.; 6 (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - Conferences, 1956-1977.; 25 (Box 6, Folder 176-177)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973.; 9 (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - Financial Records, 1960; 60 (Box 6, Folder 179)
  - Minutes, 1965-1973.; 25 (Box 6, Folder 180)
  - Publications, 1964-1975.; 6 (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - Weekly Reports, 1966-1968.; 160 (Box 6, Folder 182)